[Music]
foreign
consumption May contribute to a lower
risk of dying prematurely moderate Apple
consumption meaning like man Apple two
are weak was associated with a 20 lower
risk of dying from all causes put
together whereas those who ate an apple
a day had a 35 lower risk you'll often
hear me talking about a lower higher
risk of mortality what does that mean I
mean isn't the risk of dying 100
for everyone eventually let's look at
some survival curves to help visualize
if you follow thousands of older women
over time for example you might see a
survival curve like this
um they all start out alive but over a
period of 15 years nearly half succumb
okay but this is the survival curve of
those who rarely if ever ate apples less
than 20 a year those averaging more than
like a half a small apple a day instead
fell off like this
over the same time period closer to only
about 40 percent died and those who ate
an apple a day one small apple or about
a quarter of a large apple a day did
even better survived even longer
why is that the case it seems to be less
the apples of one's eye than the apple
of ones arteries even a fraction of an
apple a day is associated with a 24
lower odds of having severe major artery
calcifications a marker of vascular
disease and if you're like duh it's a
fruit of course it's healthy the effect
was not found for pears oranges or
bananas
both these studies were done on women
but a similar effect was found for men
for apples and onions we think because
of the flavonoids naturally occurring
phytonutrients concentrated in apples
thought to improve artery function and
lower blood pressure leading to
improvements in blood flow throughout
your body and brain thereby decreasing
the risk of heart disease and strokes
but you don't know until you put it to
the test
when I first saw this paper on testing
flavonoid Rich apples I assume they had
like selectively bread or genetically
engineered some special Apple but no the
high flavonoid Apple was just did not
bowl with its peel on compared to the
loaf flavonoid Apple which was just the
exact same Apple but with the peel
removed over the next three hours
flavonoid levels in the bloodstream shut
up in the unpeeled Apple group compared
to the peeled Apple Group which
coincided with significantly improved
artery function peeled versus unpeeled
they conclude that the lower risk of
cardiovascular disease with higher Apple
consumption is most likely due to the
high concentration of flavonoids in the
skin which improve artery function
though it could be anything in the peel
all we know is that apple peels are
particularly good for us improving
artery function and lowering blood
pressure
even compared to spinach I mean give
someone about three quarters of a cup of
cooked spinach and within two to three
hours their blood pressure drops instead
eat an apple with some extra peel thrown
in and you get a similar effect
the researchers conclude that apples and
spinach almost immediately improve
artery function and lower blood pressure
what's nice about these results is that
we're talking about Whole Foods not some
supplement or extract so this could
easily translate into a natural low-cost
method of reducing the cardiovascular
risk profile of the general population
I've got more videos coming out on other
natural low-cost methods for preventing
and treating our leading killer so keep
your eyes peeled but keep your apples
unpeeled
foreign